Hi there.
Welcome to this video
where we are going to learn
about using privacy
settings in digital environments.
The goal of the video is to help you
to know what privacy settings are
and how you can make mindful choices
when you use social media applications.
In the video, firstly,
we will look at what social media is.
Following this, we will explore
what privacy are on social media apps.
Finally, we will consider
how we can make mindful choices
about our privacy settings.
People in today's world
spend a lot of time using digital devices.
Computers, smartphones,
and tablets are examples
of digital devices that make up
the digital environment around us.
Digital devices can help
us through social media applications
to connect with family and friends.
For example, we send messages
and photos using messaging apps.
Which social media applications
do you or your family use?
Privacy settings can be found on
every social media application,
and are designed to give users
the ability to decide who can see
their online profile, what content
people can see on their profile,
and if people have the ability
to contact them.
For example,
call them or send an instant message.
Different social media platforms
have different privacy settings.
Therefore, it is important to be mindful
when you sign up to a new application
and double check that the privacy
settings are going to enable you
to have control over who is
able to see your online content or not.
Most applications allow you
to have a publicly open profile
where everyone using the platform
can see your personal information.
For example, a personal photo
of you, your status, and other information
about you such as age,
gender, where you go to school.
Whilst it is nice to share photos
and your status with family and friends.
Consider whether you want all users
of the social media platform
to see these things.
Most applications track
the internet address or position
to reveal your location.
Sometimes showing the exact address.
Whilst it might be a good idea to share
your location with family members.
It is not recommended to reveal it to
everyone using the social media platform.
You might also want to consider
whether this is
something you need to share with
some of your friends.
For example,
maybe you do not want all your friends
to see that you have an appointment
with a doctor.
We see that
influences on social media post
to the whole world to gain followers,
exchanging their personal for the money
gain.
However, we should
avoid posting everything
to the whole world and carefully
consider our privacy settings
when using social media applications.
Here are some examples of questions
you might ask yourself
when setting up a new application.
Do I want my teachers at school
to see videos I post with my friends?
Do I want to be messaged by anybody
using the social media platform?
Or only people who are
in my phone contact list?
Do I want complete strangers
to see my summer holiday photos?
Do I want anybody to see where
I am located on the map any time?
Be mindful.
Who do you want to give access
to your online content?
You can think about this
and maybe discuss it with a parent
before checking the privacy settings
of any applications that you have.
One thing to consider is
that even if you have control
over your own privacy settings,
others that you share content with
might not have control
over their privacy settings.
This can lead to content
about you being shared more widely via
someone else's social media applications.
Be mindful.
Check your own privacy settings
and inform others of your right to choose
what content about you is shared
via their online platforms.
So in this short video,
we learned that we are
part of the digital environment.
When we are using
social media applications,
privacy settings are designed
to give users the ability to decide who
can see their online profile,
what content people can see on their profile,
and if people have the ability
to contact them or not.
We can be mindful and make
good choices about these privacy settings
by asking ourselves, who do
I want to give access to my online content?
Thank you for watching.
Do not forget to watch
other videos in our series.